Guide to the Marguerite Young Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Marguerite Young papers
1925-1999
YCAL MSS 547
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
74.5
(86 boxes)
The Marguerite Young Papers document the work of writer Marguerite Young. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, audiovisual material, notebooks, research files, printed material, photographs, artwork, realia, and financial papers spanning the years 1925 to 1999. The bulk of the collection consists of Young's drafts of writings, correspondence, and audiovisual material. Writings include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, printed versions, notes, and notebooks of her writings, including Angel in the Forest: A Fairy Tale of Two Utopias; Miss Macintosh, My Darling; and Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs. Correspondence includes letters from friends and colleagues regarding her professional and personal life. Audiovisual material consists of sound recordings and one unidentified film, including the 1974 to 1975 radio production of Miss Macintosh, My Darling read by various authors and actors for WBAI-FM Pacifica Radio. Other papers include photographs, clippings, financial papers, personal papers, personal effects, and realia..
Young, Marguerite, 1908-1995
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Marguerite Young on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1993 and from Daphne Nowling on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2000. Donated by Margaret Hamilton, 1999 and Charles Ruas, 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile Materials in boxes 28-36 and 83 (audiovisual material) and box 37 (printed material) may be consulted only with permission of the appropriate curator. Reference copies of most sound recordings are available and are noted when present. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Printed material received with the collection was removed for separate cataloging and can be accessed by searching Orbis (Yale's Online Catalog).
Marguerite Young (1908-1995)
Marguerite Young, American author of poetry, fiction, non-fiction, and criticism. Young was born on August 28, 1908 in Indianapolis, Indiana and died on November 17, 1995 in New York City. Her published works include Prismatic Ground (1937), Moderate Fable (1944), Angel in the Forest: A Fairy Tale of Two Utopias (1945), Miss Macintosh, My Darling (1965), and Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs (1999). Her articles, book reviews, and poetry appeared in magazines and newspapers.
Scope and Contents
The Marguerite Young Papers document the work of writer Marguerite Young. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, audiovisual material, notebooks, research files, printed material, photographs, artwork, realia, and financial papers spanning the years 1925 to 1999. The bulk of the collection consists of Young's drafts of writings, correspondence, and audiovisual material. Writings include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, printed versions, notes, and notebooks of her writings, including Angel in the Forest: A Fairy Tale of Two Utopias; Miss Macintosh, My Darling; and Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs. Correspondence includes letters from friends and colleagues regarding her professional and personal life. Audiovisual material consists of sound recordings and one unidentified film, including the 1974 to 1975 radio production of Miss Macintosh, My Darling read by various authors and actors for WBAI-FM Pacifica Radio. Other papers include photographs, clippings, financial papers, personal papers, personal effects, and realia.
Arrangement
Organized into four groupings: I. January 1993 Acquisition, 1925-1995. II. December 1999 Acquisition, 1966-1995. III. January 2000 Acquisition, circa 1940-1994. IV. August 2000 Acquisition, 1999.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Photographs; Sound recordings; Young, Marguerite, 1908-1995
- December 1993 Acquisition, 1925-1995; Series I; 29; (37 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into five series: Correspondence, Writings, Sound Recordings, Photographs, and Printed Material.
  Scope and Contents
  Formerly classified as Uncat Za MS 314.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Marguerite Young on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1994.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 28-36 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Correspondence
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. A small amount of first name only, family, and unidentified correspondence is filed at the end of the subseries.
    - A-C, 21 (Box 1)
    - C-H, 26 (Box 2)
    - H-M, 29 (Box 3)
    - M-S, 30 (Box 4)
    - S-W, 25 (Box 5)
    - Y-Z, 7 (Box 6)
    - First name only, 22 (Box 6)
    - Family (Box 6)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 3 (Box 6)
  - Writings, 1937-1995
    - Untitled "short pieces" (Box 7)
    - Angel in the Forest: A Fairy Tale of Two Utopias, 7 (Box 7)
    - Unidentified, likely part of Angel in the Forest: A Fairy Tale of Two Utopias, 4 (Box 7)
    - Diary of Anaïs Nin, Volume 1 (1931-1934), 3 (Box 10)
      Includes corrections by Young
    - Various, 37 (Box 8)
    - Miss Macintosh, My Darling, 8 (Box 8)
    - Miss Macintosh, My Darling, 11 (Box 9)
    - Miss Macintosh, My Darling, 7 (Box 10)
    - Miss Macintosh, My Darling bound typescript with corrections, 7 (Box 11)
    - Miss Macintosh, My Darling bound typescript with corrections, 6 (Box 12)
    - Miss Macintosh, My Darling, 11 (Box 13)
    - Poetry, 2 (Box 13)
    - Unidentified various writing drafts, 11 (Box 14)
    - Unidentified various writing drafts, 39 (Box 15)
    - Unidentified various writing drafts, 34 (Box 16)
    - Unidentified various writing drafts, 7 (Box 17)
    - Various printed versions of writing drafts
  - Audiovisual Materials
    Bracketed numbers represent quantity.
    - Sound recordings
      - Miss MacIntosh, My Darling reading for WBAI-FM Pacifica Radio. Readers included Anaïs Nin, Marion Seldes, Alice Playten, H. M. Koutoukas, Leo Lerman, Michael Wagger, Novella Nelson, Osceola Archer, Owen Dodson, Wyatt Cooper, Michael Higgins, Anne Fremantle, Peggy Cass, Ruth Ford, Earle Hymen, and Daisy Alden
        Reference copies available for all readings of Miss Macintosh, My Darling. Photocopies of reel-to-reel boxes with program descriptions are filed at the beginning of Box 24.
        Boxes 28-34 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Chapter I read by Betty Lou Holland (audiotape reel), 1974 November 30; 1 (Box 28, Item barcode 39002109978586)
          Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" read by Marian Seldes, chapter 2, part one (audiotape reel), 1974 December 21; 1 (Box 28, Item barcode 39002109978578)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Marian Seldes reads the conclusion of chapter 2 about the opium lady, 1974 December 28; 1 (Box 28, Item barcode 39002109978560)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Alice Playten reading chapter 3 (audiotape reel), 1974 December 10; 1 (Box 28, Item barcode 39002109978594)
        - "Miss Mac, My Darling", Chap. 6, Part I, reading Dolores Brandon (audiotape reel), 1975 October 11; 1 (Box 28, Item barcode 39002109978602)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Tessa Kaner reads from chapters 16, 17 (audiotape reel), 1975 January 11; 1 (Box 28, Item barcode 39002109978610)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", H. M. Koutoukas reads chapter 18: rape scene (audiotape reel), 1972 May 10; 1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002109978636)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Leo Lerman reads chapter 25 reading "Experiment". Intro on M.Y. and postscript to Mr. Spitzer reading (audiotape reel), 1975 January 25; 1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002109978644)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Michael Wager reads chapter 29, part one, the Butterflies, which poses the question: Is the transformation of the Chrysalis into a butterfly, nature's metaphor for the survival of the soul after death? (audiotape reel), 1975 April 26; 1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002109978651)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Part I of Chap. 61 - John Ford Noonan reading (audiotape reel), 1975 October 18; 1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002109978669)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Michael Wager reads the conclusion of Chapter 29, "The Butterfies" (audiotape reel), 1975 May 11; 1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002109978677)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Osceola Archer reads from chapter 64 about the bald childhood (audiotape reel), 1975 May 17; 1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002109978628)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Michael Higgins reads chapter 68, "The Hangman's Tale" (audiotape reel), 1975 February 8; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002109978503)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Wyatt Cooper reads chapter 66, "The Arctic Explorer" (audiotape reel), 1975 February 15; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002109978511)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", chapter 65, Owen Dodson (audiotape reel), 1975 March 11; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002109978529)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Owen Dodson will read chapter 65 about Mr. Bonebreaker, The Bible Salesman (audiotape reel), 1975 March 8; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002109978537)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Osceola Archer reads the conclusion of ch. 64, "The Bald Childhood of Miss MacIntosh" (audiotape reel), 1975 May 24; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002109978545)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", the conclusion of chapter 29 read by Michael Wagner (audiotape reel), 1975 August 15; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002109978552)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Anne Fremantle reads chapter 70, about Mrs. Hogden the arithmetic teacher., 1975 February 22; 1; 01:02:33; Static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002109978388)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Chapter 73 read by Tessa Sapan Kaner, 1975 March 22; 1; 00:55:54; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002109978396)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Madeleine Thornton Sherwood reads chapter 77, part one. / Community News Report (1 of 2), 1975 July 11 and September 20; 1; 00:35:15; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002109978404)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Madeleine Thornton Sherwood reads chapter 77, Esther Longtree pursued by the shadow child, part II (2 of 2), 1975 June 28; 1; 00:35:05; Static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002109978412)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", chapter 79, Marian Seldes, Part I (1 of 2), 1975 April 20; 1; 00:55:34; Static can be heard on the tape. Audio in the right channel drops out for about a minute from about 13:00. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002109978420)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Marian Seldes reads the conclusion of chapt. 79. "The Woman Who Was My Father.", part II (2 of 2), 1975 April 19; 1; 00:58:19; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002109978438)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Ruth Ford reads chap. 75: Esther Longtree infanticide. (audiotape reel), 1975 March 29; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002109978446)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Earle Hymen reads part I of chapt. 81, Esther Longtree and the little toy salesman. (1 of 2 audiotape reels), 1975 May 31; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002109978453)
        - Earle Hymen reads chapt. 81 of "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling". "The Little Toy Salesman Shipwrecked", part 2 (2 of 2 audiotape reels), 1975 June 14; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002109978461)
        - "Miss Mac, My Darling"; chap. 82, Daisy Alden reading (audiotape reel), [1974-1975] October 25; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002109978479)
        - Anaïs Nin introduces Marguerite Young on "Angel in the Forest: Site of 2 Utopias", 1) Religious 2) Robert Owen, Founder of the British Labor Movement, Part I (audiotape reel), 1974 November 17; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002109978495)
        - Anaïs Nin introduces Marguerite Young, interview by Charles Ruas (audiotape reel), 1974 November 10; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002109978487)
        - Anais Nin introduces Marguerite Young: "Interview: "Angel in the Forest" on 2 Utopias, Part II of III, 1974-1975; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002109979519)
        - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", Chapter 76, [1974-1975] June 23; 1; 00:42:32 (Box 34, Item barcode 39002109978339)
        - "Miss MacIntosh" - Judy Catlin, unedited (1 of 2), [1974-1975]; 1; 01:05:49 (Box 34, Item barcode 39002109978347)
        - "Miss MacIntosh" - Judy Catlin, unedited (2 of 2), [1974-1975]; 1; 00:06:38; Audio in the right channel drops for a moment at the beginning of the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 34, Item barcode 39002109978354)
        - Betty Lou Holland, Chapter 82, Stone Deaf Man, [1974-1975]; 1; 00:38:29; Occasional drop outs in the audio can be heard. (Box 34, Item barcode 39002109978362)
        - "Miss M", Dolores Brandon, Chap. 75, edited, 1975 July 1; 1; 00:32:46 (Box 34, Item barcode 39002109978370)
        - Audiocassettes, 1974-1975
          Box 35 (audiovisual material): restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Betty Lou Holland reads Chapter 1. (c1), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979626)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Marian Seldes reads chapter two, pt. I (c2), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979592)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Marian Seldes reads the concl. of chap. two (c3), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979600)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. H.M. Koutoukas reads chapter 18. (c4), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979618)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Leo Lerman reads Chapter 25. (c5), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979634)
          - "Miss MacInt." #25, Charles [?] (c6), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979642)
          - Michael Wager 1 and 2, Chap[ter] 29, Part 1 (c7), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979659)
          - Michael Wager 3 and 4, Chap[ter] 29, Part II (1 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979675)
          - Untitled (c8) (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979667)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Michael Wager reads Chapter 29. (c9), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979683)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Michael Wager reads the concl(usion) of Chap[ter] 29. (c10), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979691)
          - Ruth Ford, Chap[ter] 80 (c11), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979709)
          - Osceola Archer, Chap[ter] 64, Part 2 (c12), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979717)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Owen Dodson reads Chapter 65. (c13), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979725)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Wyatt Cooper reads Chapter 66. (c14), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979733)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Michael Higgins reads Chapter 68. (c15), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979741)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Anne Fremantle reads Chapter 70 (c16), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979758)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling", ch. 79, pt. 2 (c17), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979766)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young - Tessa Kaner reads Chapter 73 (c18), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979774)
          - "Miss MacIntosh, My Darling" by Marguerite Young. Earle Hymen reads Chapter 81. (Part I and Conclusion) (c19), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979782)
          - Marguerite Young (c20), undated; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002109979790)
        - Miss M...., Ch. 6, Pt. II (1 of 3 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002109979527)
        - Miss M...., Ch. 6, Pt. II (2 of 3 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002109979535)
        - Miss M..., Ch. 6, Pt. II (3 of 3 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002109979543)
        - Miss M. Dolores Brandon, Ch. 6, PT III (audiotape reel), undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002109979584)
        - Miss M. Dolores Brandon, ch. 6, Pt. IV (audiotape reel), 1975 September 25; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002109979568)
        - Novella Nelson #1, ch. 30 (audiotape reel), undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002109979550)
        - Miss M. Robert Heide Reading, Ch. 59 (audiotape reel), undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002109979576)
      - "WBAI-FM Pacifica Radio, Brian Moore reads a chapter of The Lonely Passion of Judith Hearne, followed by an interview with Charles Ruas", 1976 March 19; 1; 00:36:31 (Box 36, Item barcode 39002109978321)
      - "WNYC, Absence of Silence, Marguerite Young interview with Matthew Paris", 1977 November; 1; 01:53:27; Static can be heard on the tape. Drop outs in the audio can be heard throughout the program. (Box 36, Item barcode 39002109978313)
      - "Marguerite Young's reading, Ruth Stephen Poetry Center, University of Arizona, PMM Auditorium", 1966 February 16; 1; 01:04:16; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. Volume increases gradually at about 01:02 until the end of the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 36, Item barcode 39002109978305)
    - Film
      - 16mm film (50' reel), unidentified content [1], undated
  - Photographs
    - Photographs and color slide, 13 (Box 18)
    - Photographs
  - Printed Material, 1930-1995
    - Printed material, 55 (Box 19)
    - Printed material, 37 (Box 20)
    - Printed material, 27 (Box 21)
    - Printed material, 36 (Box 22)
    - Printed material, 64 (Box 23)
    - Scrapbook of clippings
    - Printed material
    - Printed material, 1965-1995; 6
    - Printed material, 1965-1995; 5
    - Research Material, 14 (Box 24)
    - Clippings
  - Oversize
    - Photographs (Box 25)
    - Writings (Box 25)
    - Scrapbook of clippings (Box 25)
    - Printed material (Box 25)
    - Printed material, 6 (Box 26)
    - Printed material, 5 (Box 27)
  - Restricted Fragile
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of most sound recordings are available and are noted when present. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Printed Material (Box 37)
- December 1999 Acquisition, 1966-1995; Series II; 1; (1 box)
  Arranged by material type.
  Formerly classified as Uncat ZA MS 649.
  Purchased from Daphne Nowling on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2000.
  - Documents related to theft of Young's belongings from her apartment, 1983-1988 (Box 38)
  - Clippings on Young, 1966-1990 (Box 38)
  - Material related to Young's memorial service, 1995 (Box 38)
  - Script for play based on Miss Macintosh, My Darling, undated (Box 38)
  - Correspondence relating to writing of Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 1992 (Box 38)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Incorporated contract with Young for Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 1994 (Box 38)
  - Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, photocopies of typescript draft, undated; 22 (Box 38)
- January 2000 Acquisition, circa 1940-1994; Series III; 45; (46 boxes)
  Formerly classified as Uncat ZA MS 630.
  Donated by Margaret Hamilton, 2000.
  The bulk of the acquisition contains writing drafts and notebooks. Most writing drafts relate to Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs. Other papers include correspondence, financial papers, printed materials, and photographs. Realia includes woven fabric, tin boxes, a bracelet, and artwork. Seven audiocassettes filed at the end of the acquisition include readings of Miss Macintosh, My Darling for WBAI-FM Pacifica Radio and a lecture.
  Box 83 (audiovisual material): restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, typescript draft and photocopies of typescript draft, 21 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence, 2 (Box 40)
  - Financial papers (Box 40)
  - Unidentified writing drafts and writings of others, 16 (Box 40)
  - Clippings on Young, 5 (Box 40)
  - Miss MacIntosh, My Darling, typescript drafts corrected, 16 (Box 41)
  - Writing drafts, notebooks, and printed versions of writings, 11 (Box 42)
  - Writing drafts and notebooks, 20 (Box 43)
  - Writing drafts, notebooks, and printed versions of writings, 16 (Box 44)
  - Writing drafts, notebooks, printed versions of writings, correspondence, printed material, and personal papers, 20 (Box 45)
  - Writing drafts, notebooks, agendas, and correspondence, 22 (Box 46)
  - Financial papers and correspondence, 11 (Box 47)
  - Writings drafts and notebooks, 12 (Box 48)
  - Writings drafts, 12 (Box 49)
  - Writings drafts and notebooks, 12 (Box 50)
  - Writings drafts and printed material, 13 (Box 51)
  - Writing drafts, printed material, and correspondence, 18 (Box 52)
  - Writing drafts, printed material, and correspondence, 20 (Box 53)
  - Notebooks, 6 (Box 54)
  - Writing drafts, 6 (Box 54)
  - Financial correspondence, 8 (Box 54)
  - Writing drafts, 16 (Box 55)
  - Writing drafts, clippings, notebook, and correspondence, 12 (Box 56)
  - Writing drafts, notebook, printed versions, printed material, and financial correspondence, 16 (Box 57)
  - Correspondence, financial papers, and printed material, 11 (Box 58)
  - Notebooks for Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 9 (Box 59)
  - Notebooks and writing drafts for Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 12 (Box 60)
  - Writing drafts of Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 16 (Box 61)
  - Writing drafts of Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 3 (Box 62)
  - Writing drafts, 6 (Box 62)
  - Printed material and notes, 3 (Box 62)
  - Writing drafts, 3 (Box 62)
  - Writing drafts, 13 (Box 63)
  - Writing drafts, 8 (Box 64)
  - Notebooks, 6 (Box 64)
  - Correspondence, printed material, and notebooks, 15 (Box 65)
  - Writing drafts of Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 17 (Box 66)
  - Writing drafts and printed material, 17 (Box 67)
  - Notebooks, 8 (Box 68)
  - Writing drafts, notebooks, and printed material, 12 (Box 69)
  - Writing drafts of Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 10 (Box 70)
  - Printed material, 2 (Box 70)
  - Writing drafts, 17 (Box 71)
  - Writing drafts, notebooks, and writings of others, 11 (Box 72)
  - Writing drafts, 11 (Box 73)
  - Notebooks, 3 (Box 73)
  - Notebooks, 12 (Box 74)
  - Notebooks, 7 (Box 75)
  - Writing drafts, 4 (Box 75)
  - Writing drafts of Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 3 (Box 75)
  - Writing drafts of Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs, 13 (Box 76)
  - Writing drafts, 5 (Box 76)
  - Writing drafts, 8 (Box 77)
  - Correspondence, 6 (Box 77)
  - Writing drafts, 4 (Box 78)